dyson.com 2016-10-14

# Privacy Policy

#### August 2016

### Introduction

At Dyson we are committed to ensuring that your personal information is protected and never misused.

Our privacy policy explains what personal information we collect, why we collect it, how we use it, the controls you have over your personal information and the procedures that we have in place to protect your privacy. It applies to personal information we collect through our Dyson websites, through Dyson apps (including Dyson Link) and through our connected products (explained in more detail below). 

By sharing your personal information with us, and by continuing to use our websites, apps and connected products, you confirm that you have read and understood the terms of this privacy policy. We take responsibility for the personal information we collect about you, and we aim to be transparent about how we handle it, and give you control over it.

In this privacy policy, when we refer to "Dyson", "us", "we" or "our", we mean the Dyson group company or companies which provide you with the Dyson websites, apps or connected products. In this policy, we refer to all Dyson group companies as the "Dyson Group". Information on which Dyson group company or companies are responsible for any personal information collected about you, is available on our Privacy Portal by clicking on the tab for your country (<http://www.dyson.com/change-country.aspx>) If you have any questions, comments or concerns about any aspect of this policy or how Dyson handles your information please email our Privacy Team at [privacy@dyson.com](mailto:privacy@dyson.com).

##  Privacy Principles 

Privacy policies can be complicated. We have tried to make ours as clear and as accessible as possible. To help, we have also summarised how we handle your personal information at Dyson in our privacy principles below. These principles demonstrate our commitment to protecting your privacy and handling your personal information in the right way and as you would expect it to be handled. 

At Dyson we:

  1. Will only ask for or collect the personal information we need to provide and improve the service, products and experiences our customers expect.
  2. Give you control over the personal information we hold about you to ensure it is accurate and reflects your preferences.
  3. Make sure your personal information is always secure and protected
  4. Are fair and transparent about how we use the personal information we hold.
  5. Only use your personal information for the purpose that you trusted us to use it for.
  6. We never sell your information and only share it as outlined in our privacy policy or when you ask us to.
  7. Respect your choices and will inform you if there are changes that affect your personal information or how we use it. 
  8. Take responsibility for the personal information that we hold about you.

##  What personal information do we collect? 

We are not interested in collecting every personal detail about you. Our main reason for collecting your personal information is to provide and improve the service, products and experiences that you and our customers expect from us. 

Personal information is defined slightly differently across the world. To guarantee your privacy and the protection of your information, we define it as any information that could be used to identify you or another individual. 

We collect personal information from you in a number of different ways; you may share that information with us, or we may collect it using other means. In this section, we explain the different ways we collect personal information from you and some ways in which that information will be used. For more detail on how we use your personal information, please see the section titled "How do we use your personal information?".

### Information you share with us

We collect personal information that you share with us when you contact us or interact with us through our website, apps, email, phone or otherwise. You can decide not to provide certain information, or ask that any information you have previously shared is removed. If you do so, you may not be able to take full advantage of our products, technology and service. 

For example, you may provide information to us when you contact our customer service teams, place an order, register your warranty, complete a survey, competition or questionnaire, update your preferences and account information, connect through a Dyson app or rate one of our products on our website.

Through these interactions you may share with us: your name, address, e-mail address, contact number and payment information. You may also share details of other people; for example, if you have bought a Dyson product for that other person or if you register another person for a Dyson app. In those circumstances, you will need to check with that person that they are happy for you to share their personal information with us, and for us to use it in accordance with this privacy policy. 

### Information from Dyson products and apps

As well as the personal information you share with us about yourself and your Dyson product, we may collect and handle personal information directly from your Dyson connected products and Dyson apps. A connected product is a Dyson product that is “smart”, internet enabled or operated through a Dyson app. 

We may collect information about your use of our connected products or apps, to help us optimise their performance and your experience of using them. We may also collect internet protocol (IP) and/or media access control (MAC) identifier information about your mobile device.

Some of the information we collect from your use of our connected products and apps may enable us to determine the location of your connected product. This data is collected so that we can understand the location and environmental conditions in which your connected product is operating; for example, by giving an indication of the environment in which it operates, which helps us to optimise the performance of the connected product. 

Some of our connected products may not be able to operate without collecting location information, or other personal information, and so by registering for the app and using a connected product you agree to this use of the information. 

### Information from your online interactions

We collect and store limited personal information and anonymous, aggregate statistics from all visitors to our websites, whether you actively provide us with that information or merely browse our websites. The information we collect includes the internet protocol (IP) address of the device you are using, the browser software you use, your operating system, the date and time of access, the internet address of the website from which you link through to our website and information on how you use our websites.

We use this information so that we can see how long our websites take to load, how they are used, the number of visitors to the different sections of our websites, and what information visitors look at most. It also helps identify any part of our website that isn’t working as well as it should - so we can fix things and make our website better for you and other users.

We do not link information collected from your online interactions with any records we may have of you as a customer of Dyson.

### Cookies

When you use our websites we may also use information collected by cookies. "Cookies" are small text files that websites save onto your device via your web browser. They’ve been around since the mid-1990’s and are one of the most widely used technologies on the internet.

Some cookies that we use at Dyson will collect personal information about you. Any personal information that is collected will be used in accordance with this privacy policy. By continuing to use our websites, you accept that cookies may be set on your device. 

For further information, including on the types of cookies that we use and how to manage cookies placed on our websites, please refer to our [cookies policy](http://www.dyson.com/support/cookies.aspx). Please note that we do not currently respond to Do Not Track (DNT) signals. 

### Email Communications

As long as you are happy for us to do so, we would like to keep you posted on anything that's happening at Dyson which we think you might like to know about; whether it’s our latest product announcements, owner offers or upcoming events, we want to make sure you’re happy with the communications you receive from us. You can find out how to update or change whether you would like to hear from us, or stop us contacting you, in the section below titled ‘How can you change the way that we contact you?' 

Sometimes we receive notifications when you open an e-mail from us; we use these statistics to help our teams to make our e-mails as interesting as possible by providing you with interesting content and experiences. 

### Social Media

We love interacting with you on social media. You may use social media to contact us about your Dyson products, or to let people know what you think about your Dyson product. We review publically available social media and online sites to get a better understanding of what people are saying about us, and our products, technology and services and to assist consumers who prefer to contact us through social media.

The information we collect from social media and online sites sometimes includes personal information that has been put online and is publically available. We make sure any information we use is properly credited to its source or is made anonymous. 

These online and social media sites may have their own privacy policies explaining how they use and share your personal information. You should carefully review those privacy policies before you use these sites to make sure that you are happy with how your personal information is being collected and shared.

##  How do we use your personal information? 

Our main reason for collecting and using your personal information is to provide and improve the service, products and experiences that you expect from us. 

### Information you share with us

We use the personal information you share with us in the following ways: 

  * To respond to your queries and requests;
  * To communicate with you;
  * To provide services and support for our products;
  * For customer satisfaction surveys and to allow us to improve your experience should you need support from one of our experts;
  * To provide updates to you about any changes to Dyson’s policies, terms and conditions and any other matters which we may need to tell you;
  * As long as you are happy for us to do so, to tell you about our other products and services; and
  * To provide you with essential service updates about your Dyson products.

### Information from Dyson products and apps

We use the personal information we collect from Dyson products and apps, by itself and in combination with your customer record (the information you share with us), in the following ways: 

  * To monitor the performance and stability of our products;
  * To improve our products, technology and services;
  * To monitor your use of our connected products and apps so that we can optimise their performance and your experience of using them; 
  * To provide updates and services to our connected products (which includes updates and upgrades to software and our apps); and
  * For profiling and statistical analysis of how our products are used. 

### Information from your online interactions

We use the personal information from your online interactions (collected using cookies):

  * To customise the way that you shop with us in the future; for example, by showing you products and offers that we think you might like; and 
  * For profiling and statistical analysis of product popularity, and of our customers' behaviour when using our websites or apps. 

### Other potential uses of your personal information

We may also use your personal information:

  * To assist in any disputes, claims or investigations relating to your Dyson product or warranty matters; and
  * To comply with our legal obligations. 

##  Dyson owner support 

From time-to-time, we may use your personal information to help you with the Dyson products you own. We do this in various ways, including e-mail, post, SMS, phone and in-app notifications. 

As a user of our products or services, we will send you the following support communications:

  * Helpful information about your Dyson product or the Dyson service you use;
  * Reminders about how to carry out maintenance on your Dyson product for optimal performance;
  * Alerts for recommended app or software updates or upgrades that may improve the performance of your product;
  * Information about how and where to get help from Dyson experts should you need support;
  * Information about your Dyson warranty;
  * Alerts regarding any important product safety or recall announcements; and  
  * Requests for your feedback on how we perform after you have used a Dyson product or service.

We will send you support communications unless you change your preferences, or tell us that you want to stop receiving support communications from us. Please see the section below for more information about how to do this. 

If your details change, please let us know so that we can continue to stay in touch.

##  Links to third party websites 

We may provide links to other websites which are not operated and controlled by Dyson.

We have no control over and are not responsible for the content of those sites or how the third parties responsible for them collect and use your personal information. We do not endorse or make any representations about third party websites. 

Third party websites may have their own privacy policies explaining how they use and share your personal information. You should carefully review those privacy policies before you use these websites to make sure that you are happy with how your personal information is being collected and shared.

##  How long do we keep your personal information? 

We only keep your personal information for as long as we need to, to be able to use it for the reasons given in this privacy policy, and for as long as we are required to keep it by law.

##  Your controls and choices 

We give you control over the personal information we collect about you, to ensure it is accurate and reflects your preferences. 

You have the right to access, update and amend personal information that we hold about you. You can also ask us to remove personal information about you or limit its use (see previous section on updating your preferences). 

If the law in your country allows us to impose a fee for giving you access, we will communicate this to you in response to your request. 

We will not charge you to update, amend or remove your personal information. 

If you would like to access, update or amend your personal information or, if you would like us to remove personal information that we hold about you, or limit its use, please email [privacy@dyson.com](mailto:privacy@dyson.com).

##  How do we protect your personal information? 

We are committed to protecting your personal information.  We use appropriate technical and organisational measures, including encryption, to protect your personal information and privacy, and review those regularly.  We protect your personal information using a combination of physical and IT security controls, including access controls that restrict and manage the way in which your personal information and data is processed, managed and handled.  We also ensure that our staff are adequately trained in protecting your personal information.  Our procedures mean that we may occasionally request proof of identity before we share your personal information with you. 

In the unlikely event that we do suffer a security breach which compromises our protection of your personal information and we need to let you know about it, we will do so.

##  Data transfers, storage and the global handling of your personal information 

Dyson is headquartered in the United Kingdom (UK). 

We collect personal information in the country in which you live. We then host and store that information in the European Economic Area (EEA). Those third parties that we share your personal information with may handle or transfer your personal information outside of the UK, and outside of the EEA, to other countries in which they have facilities.

We will make sure that both any transfer of your personal information by us or by the third parties that we share your personal information with, and our handling of your personal information, complies with those laws which apply to us.  In any case, our transfer, storage and handling of your personal information will continue to be governed by this privacy policy. 

By submitting your personal information to us, and by using our websites, apps or connected products, you agree to us transferring, storing and handling your personal information in this way.

##  Children 

Dyson's websites, apps and products are not directed at children. We do not knowingly collect any personal information from children.

If you are a child, please do not attempt to become a registered user of our websites, apps or products or otherwise provide us with any personal information. If we learn that we have inadvertently obtained personal information from a child, we will delete that information as soon as possible.  

If you are aware of a child who has provided their personal information to us, please contact us at [privacy@dyson.com](mailto:privacy@dyson.com).

##  Dyson Careers 

The Dyson careers website uses your personal information to provide you with information or services that you have requested including supporting your application for employment at Dyson. 

For more information about how we use your personal information when using the Dyson careers website please refer to <http://careers.dyson.com/standalone/privacy/>

##  Changes to this privacy policy 

We will review and update this privacy policy at least once a year and will note the date it was last updated below.

If we change our privacy policy, we will post the details of the changes below. If we have your e-mail address, we may also e-mail you with information on those changes. If we need to, we will also ask you to confirm that you are happy with those changes. 

We stand behind the commitments we have made. We will never change our policies and practices in a way that will offer less protection for personal information that we already have about you without your consent.

**This privacy policy was last reviewed and updated in August 2016.**

##  Previous changes to this privacy policy 

August 2016 – Minor amends for Global Privacy Portal launch clarifying Dyson partners and marketing via social platforms

March 2016 – Global Privacy Portal launched with new privacy policies.

##  Translations of this privacy policy 

This privacy policy has been translated from English into the official language of a number of different countries. We have done this to make sure that the policy is clear and accessible to all users of our websites, apps and connected products. If there are any conflicts or inconsistencies between the translated versions of this privacy policy, the English version will prevail.
